<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS Cloud Intelligence Dashboards</title>
    <link>https://catalog.workshops.aws/awscid/en-US</link>
    <description>The Cloud Intelligence Dashboards is an open-source framework from AWS to get high-level and granular insight into their cost and usage data</description>
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws-samples/aws-cudos-framework-deployment/refs/heads/rss_feed/changes/cloud-intelligence-dashboards.rss"
                 rel="self"
                 type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 12:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-us</language>

    <item>
      <title>CUDOS update v5.5</title>
      <link>https://catalog.workshops.aws/awscid/en-US/dashboards/foundational/cudos-cid-kpi</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://github.com/aws-samples/aws-cudos-framework-deployment/blob/main/changes/CHANGELOG-cudos.md#cudos---55</guid>
      <description>CUDOS update to v5.5</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <ul>
        <li>DynamoDB: Refactored visuals to improve user experience and simplify navigation. 'DynamoDB Accounts by Category' visuals replaced with 'DynamoDB Cost per Account' and 'DynamoDB Cost per Usage Type Group'</li>
        <li>DynamoDB: New section 'DynamoDB Provisioned Capacity - Reservations Savings Estimation' which allows to calculate estimated savings for Amazon DynamoDB reserved capacity based on custom commitment amount.</li>
        <li>DynamoDB: New section 'DynamoDB Provisioned Capacity - Reservation Coverage and Usage Monitoring' which allows monitor reserved capacity coverage per region and capacity type dimensions</li>
        <li>DynamoDB: New visual 'Infrequent Access Tables Cost and Cost Efficiency Gain/Loss vs Standard Storage' which shows efficiency gains from Infrequent Access tables and also tables which could be migrated to Standard table class</li>
        <li>Monitoring and Observability: New section 'AWS Config Periodic Recording Savings Opportunities' which shows potential savings from migration to periodic configuration item recording</li>
        <li>Monitoring and Observability: New section 'Account and Regions without AWS Config' which allows to identify account and regions with AWS service usage and where AWS Config is not enabled</li>
        <li>Analytics: Improved 'QuickSight Usage Type Group' calculated field to accommodate the latest QuickSight pricing constructs</li>
        <li>AI/ML: Added Guardrails to the 'Bedrock UsageType Group' calculated field</li>
        <li>Databases: Updated action filter on 'RI Coverage per region | engine | instance type or family' to be applied to 'Top 20 instances' allowing to focus on resources which belong to particular RI dimension</li>
        <li>Compute: Bug fix for 'EKS Extended Support Cost per Account' visual. Added missing filter for Last 30 days.
    </ul>
  ]]> 
    </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCAD Containers Cost Allocation Dashboard update to v1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://catalog.workshops.aws/awscid/en-US/dashboards/additional/scad-containers-cost-allocation</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://github.com/aws-samples/aws-cudos-framework-deployment/blob/main/changes/CHANGELOG-scad-cca.md#scad-containers-cost-allocation-dashboard---v100</guid>
      <description>SCAD Containers Cost Allocation Dashboard update to v1.0.0</description>
      <content:encoded>Added support to view Net Amortized Cost in "View Cost As" control in all sheets. Removed "Exclude last 1 month" from all date range controls to prevent "No Data" (because Split Cost Allocation Data for EKS starts filling data only in current month)
        Fixed issue where all split cost and usage metrics were lower than they should be, for pods on EC2 instances that were running for less than a full hour
        Fixed aggregation issues for usage metrics in Athena views</content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>CUDOS update to v5.4</title>
      <link>https://catalog.workshops.aws/awscid/en-US/dashboards/foundational/cudos-cid-kpi</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://github.com/aws-samples/aws-cudos-framework-deployment/blob/main/changes/CHANGELOG-cudos.md#cudos---54</guid>
      <description>CUDOS update to v5.4</description>
      <content:encoded>CUDOS  is an in-depth, granular, and recommendation-driven dashboard to help customers dive deep into cost and usage. [new tab] Security: Introducing Security tab with cost and usage details for Security services. New tab includes visuals 'Security Spend per Service', 'Security Spend per Account' and respective detailed view sections for Amazon Cognito and Amazon GuardDuty
Security: New Amazon Cognito section with visuals 'Amazon Cognito Spend and Projected Cost for M2M App Clients and Tokens', 'Amazon Cognito Spend and Projected Cost for M2M App Clients and Tokens per Account' and 'Amazon Cognito Detailed View'
Security: New Amazon GuardDuty section with visuals 'Amazon GuardDuty Spend per UsageType', 'Amazon GuardDuty Spend per Account' and 'Accounts and Regions where Amazon GuardDuty is not enabled'
Databases: Bugfix for Storage Type categorization on 'Daily Storage Cost'
DynamoDB: Improved 'TOP 15 Candidates for Infrequent Access Tables Last 30 Days' visual to exclude tables after they migrated to Infrequent Access.</content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Health Events Dashboard v2.0.0</title>
      <link>https://catalog.workshops.aws/awscid/en-US/dashboards/advanced/health-events</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://github.com/aws-samples/aws-cudos-framework-deployment/blob/main/changes/CHANGELOG-hed.md#v200</guid>
      <description>Health Events Dashboard v2.0.0</description>
      <content:encoded>AWS Health integrates with 200+ AWS services to aggregate important information in a timely manner. AWS Health notifies you about service events, planned changes, and other account matters to help you manage your resources and take actions where necessary. Reorganized Summary tab for better flow and easy creation of targeted inventory reports of impacted resources
Requires update with cid-cli parameters: --force --recursive.</content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>CID Data Collection Framework update to v3.3.2</title>
      <link>https://github.com/awslabs/cid-framework/releases</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://github.com/awslabs/cid-framework/releases/tag/3.3.2</guid>
      <description>CID Data Collection Framework update to v3.3.2</description>
      <content:encoded>DCF centralizes data from the AWS Organization including compute, storage, databases, analytics, networking,
        mobile, developer tools, management tools, security and enterprise applications.
CHANGES: Health Events metadata schema issues - force JSON to string by @esc1144 in #192
Create cost_anomaly_data table when module is deployed by @rarmist in #194
Refactoring of Pricing Module, adding table for services availablity by @iakov-aws in #198
increase MemorySize of inventory-lambda by @habibmasri in #202</content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>New SCAD Containers Cost Allocation Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://catalog.workshops.aws/awscid/en-US/dashboards/additional/scad-containers-cost-allocation</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[New dashboard]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://github.com/aws-samples/aws-cudos-framework-deployment/blob/main/changes/CHANGELOG-scad-cca.md#scad-containers-cost-allocation-dashboard---v001</guid>
      <description>Introducing SCAD Containers Cost Allocation Dashboard</description>
      <content:encoded>Initial release&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Released to GA.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; -------</content:encoded>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
